<dashboard stylesheet="application.css">
	<label>Cisco ASA Configuration</label>

	<row>
		<html>
<h2>Steps to Configuring Cisco Security Suite for Cisco Firewalls</h2>

<p>Cisco Firewalls includes the Cisco ASA, PIX and FWSM devices.  Configuration of the Cisco Security 
Suite is a multi-step process:</p>

<ol>
<li>Decide on a Log Reception Methodology</li>
<li>Set up a Log Receiver Host</li>
<li>Configure the Logging Settings in your Cisco Firewalls</li>
<li>Configure Splunk for your Environment</li>
</ol>

<p>Please walk through the instructions below in order to properly configured the Cisco Firewall reporting.  These
instructions assume you have basic knowledge of how to commit configuration changes to your Cisco firewalls.
If you do not know how to do that, then please refer to your Cisco.</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Decide on a Log Reception Methodology</h3>

<p>The Cisco Security Suite Network Security section primarily deals with the firewall accept/deny logs.  These 
logs are generally transmitted via TCP or UDP syslog to a receiver - in this case, a Splunk Universal Forwarder.</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Set up a Log Receiver Host</h3>

<p>Ideally, you should set up an independent host that can act as a syslog receiver. You can either set up an
independent syslog receiver that sends syslog to a file, or you can accept syslog directly with the Universal
Forwarder.  This host can run any operating system.  If you are running an independent syslog receiver, then you
will find that a Linux variant is easier to handle.  Configuring an indepdenent syslog receiver is beyond the
scope of these instructions.</p>

<p>Splunk does NOT recommend using one of the Splunk indexer or search head hosts except in Proof of Concept or 
extremely low load scenarios.  The device may be virtualized, however.</p>

<p>Once you have a log receiver host, ensure you install the latest Splunk 6 Universal Forwarder on that host.
In addition, you will need to configure a log reader in inputs.conf for the host.  If you have configured an
independent syslog receiver, then you will use a monitor statement. For example, if you had arranged for your 
logs to be delivered to a host-specific directory under /var/log/cisco-fw (so that the logs are actually stored 
as /var/log/cisco-fw/HOST/*.log), then you might use the following:</p>

<pre>
[monitor:///var/log/cisco-fw/*/*.log]
host_segment = 4
source = cisco:asa
sourcetype = cisco:asa
disabled = false
</pre>

<p>If you are using PIX firewalls, then the source and sourcetype should be cisco:pix.  If you are using the FWSM
firewall services module, then the source and sourcetype should be cisco:fwsm.</p>

<p>If you are utilizing TCP-based syslog directly to the Universal Forwarder, then you might use the following 
(where A.B.C.D is the IP address of your Cisco ASA appliance and HOST is the hostname to assign to the Cisco 
ASA appliance):</p>

<pre>
[tcp://A.B.C.D:514]
host = HOST
source = cisco:asa
sourcetype = cisco:asa
disabled = false
</pre>

<p>Please make note of the TCP port that you utilize (in this case, 514) and ensure no software-based 
firewalls are blocking connections.  We don't recommend using UDP-based syslog - in high-load scenarios,
messages will be lost.  As with the monitor statement, use cisco:pix or cisco:fwsm if you have those
appliances.</p>

<p>It is possible to accept syslog from many devices by using a [tcp://:514] stanza - in this case, you
will need to use a transform to configure the source and sourcetype at index time.  You will need to place
the Splunk_TA_cisco-asa on the indexing tier as well as the universal forwarder and search heads.</p>

<p>If you wish the logs to go to an index other than main, add an index parameter to the inputs.conf
stanza.  Ensure the index is created on your indexing tier before you continue.</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Configuring Logging on your Cisco Firewall</h3>

<p>To configure logging on your Cisco Firewall, use the following command in config mode:</p>

<pre>logging host &lt;int&gt; &lt;ipaddr&gt; tcp/514</pre>

<p>The &lt;int&gt; field is the interface that the syslog data will be sent out of.  The &lt;ipaddr&gt; 
field is the IP address of your syslog collector.  If you configured a different TCP port from the standard
514, then use that in this command instead.  Remember to commit the changes.</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Configure Splunk for your Environment</h3>

<p>If you have configured Splunk to store the access logs in an alternate index, then you will need to ensure
that users can find the logs by default.  To do this, you must create a new role. For more information on this
subject, please see the <a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/6.0.1/Security/SetupuserauthenticationwithSplunk">Splunk 
Security Manual</a>.</p>

		</html>
	</row>
</dashboard>
