<dashboard stylesheet="application.css">
	<label>Cisco WSA Configuration</label>

	<row>
		<html>
<h2>Steps to Configuring Cisco Security Suite for Web Security</h2>

<p>Configuration of the Cisco Security Suite is a multi-step process:</p>

<ol>
<li>Decide on a Log Reception Methodology</li>
<li>Set up a Log Receiver Host</li>
<li>Configure the Logging Settings in your Cisco WSA</li>
<li>Set up a Role to read the Cisco WSA Logs</li>
<li>Configure the Cisco WSA Result Code Extraction</li>
<li>Configure the Cisco WSA Usage Lookup</li>
</ol>

<p>Please walk through the instructions below in order to properly configured the Cisco WSA reporting.  These
instructions assume you have basic knowledge of how to commit configuration changes to your Cisco WSA appliances.
If you do not know how to do that, then please refer to your Cisco WSA ASyncOS manual, most notably Chapter
24, which talks about Logging.</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Decide on a Log Reception Methodology</h3>

<p>The Cisco Security Suite Web Security section primarily deals with the Access Logs.  These logs may be transmitted
to a Splunk Instance via scp push, ftp push or syslog.  For the best combination of security and performance of your proxy, 
Cisco recommends utilizing scp.  For near-real-time performance, Splunk recommends a 5-minute or less transfer time.  
If you actually need real-time analysis of the Cisco WSA logs, you must choose syslog as a delivery mechanism.  Note,
however, that syslog is considered unreliable and not all data may make it to Splunk, especially in high load 
scenarios.</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Set up a Log Receiver Host</h3>

<p>Ideally, you should set up an independent host.  If using syslog, this host may run any operating system for 
which Splunk has a Universal Forwarder.  If you are using scp or ftp transfers, then you should be running a Linux
system with plenty of storage for logs.</p>

<p>Splunk does NOT recommend using one of the Splunk indexer or search head hosts except in Proof of Concept or 
extremely low load scenarios.  The device may be virtualized, however.</p>

<p>Once you have a log receiver host, ensure you install the latest Splunk 6 Universal Forwarder on that host.
In addition, you will need to configure a log reader in inputs.conf for the host.  For an scp or ftp transfer,
use a monitor stanza.  For example, if you had arranged for your logs to be delivered to a host-specific directory 
under /var/log/cisco-wsa (so that the logs are actually stored as /var/log/cisco-wsa/HOST/*.log), then you might
use the following:</p>

<pre>
[monitor:///var/log/cisco-wsa/*/*.log]
host_segment = 4
source = cisco:wsa
sourcetype = cisco:wsa:squid
disabled = false
</pre>

<p>If you are utilizing TCP-based syslog, then you might use the following (where A.B.C.D is the IP
address of your Cisco WSA appliance and HOST is the hostname to assign to the Cisco WSA appliance):</p>

<pre>
[tcp://A.B.C.D:514]
host = HOST
source = cisco:wsa
sourcetype = cisco:wsa:squid
disabled = false
</pre>

<p>Please make note of the TCP port that you utilize (in this case, 514) and ensure no software-based 
firewalls are blocking connections.  Note that syslog messages are truncated to 1024 characters which 
may cause problems in properly recording all the information needed.  We DO NOT RECOMMEND syslog push.</p>

<p>If you wish the logs to go to an index other than main, add an index parameter to the inputs.conf
stanza.  Ensure the index is created on your indexing tier before you continue.</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Configuring Logging on your Cisco WSA</h3>

<ul>
<li>Log onto your Cisco WSA as an Administrator</li>
<li>Navigate to System Administration -&gt; Log Subscriptions</li>
<li>Click on "Add Log Subscription".</li>
<li>Select Squid from the Log Type field.</li>
<li>Enter "Splunk" in the log Name field.</li>
<li>In Custom Fields, enter the following: <code>%u %&lt;Referer: %k %g %XF %q</code></li>
<li>Enter a suitable name for the log file in the File Name field</li>
<li>Enter a maximum size in bytes ( or use G for Gigabytes, M for Megabytes, K for kilobytes)</li>
<li>Choose whether or not to compress log files (this has implications for the monitor stanza above)</li>
<li>Choose a method - FTP on Remote Server, SCP on Remote Server or Syslog Push</li>
<li>Enter the information specific for the method you are using.</li>
<li>Submit and commit any changes.</li>
</ul>

<p>If you select SCP push, then the appliance displays an SSH key that you must place on the log receiver
to receive logs.</p>

<p>At this point, your Splunk instance should be receiving access log entries.  Use the search console to
verify this before continuing.</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Set up a Role to read the Cisco WSA logs</h3>

<p>If you have configured Splunk to store the access logs in an alternate index, then you will need to ensure
that users can find the logs by default.  To do this, you must create a new role. For more information on this
subject, please see the <a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/6.0.1/Security/SetupuserauthenticationwithSplunk">Splunk Security Manual</a>.</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Configure the Cisco WSA Result Code Extraction</h3>

<p>The Cisco WSA Result Code can be a different format than what is configured by default.  The format we have
defined is shown in Chapter 24 of the Cisco WSA ASyncOS for Web User Guide.  If yours differs, then you will
need to adjust the extraction.</p>

<ul>
<li>Log onto your Splunk Search Head via the web interface as an Administrator</li>
<li>Navigate to Settings -&gt; All Configurations.</li>
<li>Select the Cisco Web Security Appliance (TA-cisco-wsa) app</li>
<li>Check the box labeled "Show only objects created in this app context</li>
<li>Click on cisco-wsa-scanverdict</li>
<li>Alter the definition to match your specific output</li>
<li>Click on Save</li>
</ul>

<p>In some cases, the cisco-wsa-scanverdict won't be seen.  In this case:</p>

<ul>
<li>Log onto your Splunk Search Head as a user who can edit files</li>
<li>Go to $SPLUNK_HOME/etc/apps/TA-cisco-wsa</li>
<li>Make a new directory called "local"</li>
<li>Copy default/transforms.conf to local/transforms.conf</li>
<li>Edit the local/transforms.conf and alter the FIELDS list for cisco-wsa-scanverdict</li>
<li>Save the local/transforms.conf file, then restart the server</li>
</ul>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold">Configure the Cisco WSA Usage Lookup</h3>

<p>The Cisco WSA Usage Lookup defines whether each category is treated as Business, Personal, Legal Liability 
or Other.  You can add any custom categories to this file and change the definitions as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>Log onto your Splunk Search Head as a user who can edit files</li>
<li>Go to $SPLUNK_HOME/etc/apps/AA-cisco-wsa/lookups</li>
<li>Edit the file cisco_wsa_usage.csv with your favorite editor</li>
</ul>

<p>Since this file is overwritten on upgrade, take a copy of the updated file and place it somewhere safe.</p>

		</html>
	</row>
</dashboard>
