<dashboard stylesheet="help.css">
	<label>Cisco ESA Configuration</label>

	<row>
		<html>
<h2>Steps to Configuring Cisco Security Suite for Cisco Email Security Appliance</h2>

<p>
Splunk for Cisco ESA allows a Splunk administrator to collect Cisco ESA system logs. Once ingested, 
the log data can be analyzed directly or used as a contextual data source to correlate with other communication and authentication 
data in Splunk.
</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold; padding-top:15px">Installation of the add-on to the search head</h3>
<p>
The Splunk_TA_cisco-esa add-on needs to be installed on your Splunk search head to allow a user to use the search-time knowledge provided within the add-on. <br />
To install the add-on, do the following:

<ol>
<li>Download the app from <a href="http://apps.splunk.com/app/1761/">http://apps.splunk.com/app/1761/</a>.</li>
<li>From the Splunk web interface, click on App -> Manage Apps to open the Apps Management page in Manager.</li>
<li>Click the "Install app from file" button, locate the downloaded file and click "Upload".</li>
<li>Verify (if necessary) that the app is installed.  It should be listed in the list of apps installed within the Manager and can be found on the server at $SPLUNK_HOME/etc/apps/Splunk_TA_cisco-esa.</li>
</ol>
</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold; padding-top:15px">Receiving data from ESA on the Splunk Server</h3>

<p>
<pre>
=======       =================
| ESA |  ——>  | Splunk Server |
=======       =================
</pre>
</p>

<p>
Note: It is preferred to have a separate forwarder machine as explained below in order to to receive data from ESA
and then forward data to the Splunk server to minimize resource utilization on the Splunk server.
</p>

<p>
If you do decide to receive ESA data directly on your Splunk server, create the following directory on your Splunk server: <br />

<pre>
    $SPLUNK_HOME/etc/apps/Splunk_TA_cisco-esa/local
</pre>
</p>

<p>
To complete the setup, follow the directions below for <u>Receiving data from ESA on a Splunk Universal Forwarder (preferred)</u>.
Create the inputs.conf file within the "local" directory you created.
</p>


<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold; padding-top:15px">Receiving data from ESA on a Splunk Universal Forwarder (preferred)</h3>

<p>
<pre>
=======       ==============================       =================
| ESA |  ——>  | Splunk Universal Forwarder |  ——>  | Splunk Server |
=======       ==============================       =================
</pre>
</p>

<p>
You must configure a forwarder to collect the data from the Cisco ESA appliance.  In many cases, this will be a dedicated Linux
system that is being used as an ftp or scp repository.  Install the Universal Forwarder on this host and configure the forwarder
to forward all logs to your indexer.
</p>

<p>
To collect the data using FTP or SCP, use the following inputs.conf stanzas: <br />

<pre>

	[monitor:///var/log/cisco-esa]
	source = cisco:esa
	sourcetype = cisco:esa
	host = 
</pre>
</p>

<p>
To collect the data using UDP, use the following inputs.conf stanza: <br />

<pre>
	[udp://esa-appliance-ip:port]
	source = cisco_syslog
	sourcetype = cisco:esa
	host = esa-appliance-name
	connection_host = none
	acceptFrom = esa-appliance-ip
	disabled = false
</pre>
</p>

<p>
Repeat for each ESA appliance.  The port should be the syslog port that is configured on the Cisco ESA appliance.  If you are utilizing
a FTP or SCP copy mechanism (which is preferred), use a [monitor://] stanza instead.
</p>

<p>
Restart the indexer.
</p>

<h3 style="color:#29688A;font-weight:bold; padding-top:15px">Configure ESA to forward data</h3>

<p>
System Administration -> Log Subscriptions
</p>

		</html>
	</row>
</dashboard>
